<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Jorge Jara]]></title><description><![CDATA[Student, cat lover, SI fanboy. (he/they)]]></description><link>https://lumen.netlify.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 20:32:13 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Please Don't Abuse Voice Messages]]></title><description><![CDATA[Just a quick rant for having something published on the page.]]></description><link>https://lumen.netlify.com/posts/please-dont-abuse-voice-messages</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lumen.netlify.com/posts/please-dont-abuse-voice-messages</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick rant for having something published on the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not an extremely sociable person by any means, but I do chat pretty often with friends or classmates via IM platforms like WhatsApp. Whether it is for complaining about a shitty teacher, sending memes or sharing news, having a platform to communicate with people is a total must nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if there is something I cannot withstand is having to interrupt my Pretty Busy Workflow™ (mainly composed of YouTube binging, procrastinating and feeling anxiety at times) for having to listen to someone’s voice messages. It’s not a big deal for me if it is something occasional, but when it comes to people whose main way to send information to others is by voice messages I cannot but scream internally when I have to listen to three minute-long messages that I can’t listen at a 2x speed rate (if the folks at WhatsApp really cared about UX, they should have implemented features like this a long time ago; probably this wouldn’t be such a “problem” for me if that were the case).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a person with a relatively low attention span, and that’s the reason I like things done fast. If you’re going to spend 15 minutes in saying something that could have been said in less than 3, you lost me. I know that voice is a lot more expressive than sending a string of text with one or two emojis, but please: use them wisely. At least try to plan what you’re going to record and be concise. People like me will thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>